Love makes monsters of us all.
Crimson Peak is a horror, mystery, romance film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
In the aftermath of a family tragedy, an aspiring author is torn between love for
her childhood friend and the temptation of a mysterious outsider.
Trying to escape the ghosts of her past, she is swept away to
a house that breathes, bleeds… and remembers.
Edith Cushing, played by Mia Wasikowska.
Lady Lucille Sharpe, played by Jessica Chastain.
Sir Thomas Sharpe, played by Tom Hiddleston.
Dr. Alan McMichael, played by Charlie Hunnam.
Carter Cushing, played by Jim Beaver.
Holly, played by Burn Gorman.
Crimson Peak is a 2015 Gothic romance film directed by Guillermo del
Toro and written by del Toro and Matthew Robbins.
The film stars Mia Wasikowska, Tom Hiddleston, Jessica
Chastain, Charlie Hunnam, and Jim Beaver.
The story, set in Victorian-Era England, follows an aspiring author who travels to a remote
Gothic mansion in Cumberland, England with her new husband and his sister.
There, she must decipher the mystery behind the
ghostly visions that haunt her new home.
In 2006, a spec script written by Del Toro and Robbins was sold to
Universal Pictures, with Del Toro set to direct.
Development was delayed due to scheduling conflicts.
The film was described as a "ghost story and gothic romance" heavily inspired by
other horror films, such as The Haunting, The Innocents and The Shining.
Principal photography began at Pinewood Toronto Studios in Toronto, Ontario on February 10,
2014, with additional filming in Hamilton, and ended on May 16 that year.
The film was produced by Legendary Pictures and Del Toro's
production company, Double Dare You Productions.
Crimson Peak premiered at Fantastic Fest on September 25, 2015, and was released in
the United States on October 16, 2015, in standard and IMAX formats.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics but
underperformed at the box office,  grossing $74 million worldwide.
The film received three nominations at the 21st
Empire Awards, including Best Horror.
It received nine nominations at the 42nd Saturn Awards, winning three, including Best Horror
Film, Best Supporting Actress for Chastain and Best Production Design for Thomas E.
The film explores themes of psychopath, poison, haunted house, mining, murder.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.